[The Unclouded Soul]
[Episode 26]
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Where am I?
Is anyone here?
Hello?
Anyone around?
How beautiful.
Xiao Yao,
is this really you?
Gorgeous,
stunning—
perfect descriptions of you.
But who am I now?
Who's there?
Your Highness,
it's time for lunch.
"Your Highness"?
Am I in the imperial palace?
I am Princess Ning'an?
Yes, Your Highness.
Anything wrong?
What else?
Your Highness rarely talks to others
and enjoys reading, writing, and painting
in your bedchamber alone.
Your Highness doesn't even show
much interest in items of gold and silver.
Your Highness?
Go on.
Has the princess...
I mean, have I
been like this since childhood?
Well...
Say it.
I heard
Your Highness
was given birth by a maid.
Disdaining such humble origins,
His Majesty has always
neglected Your Highness.
Your Highness doesn't even
get to see His Majesty once in a year.
That's why Your Highness
has grown increasingly silent.
As time passes,
rumor even has it that Your Highness...
is a jinx.
Have I...
always looked like this?
Yes.
What's your name?
It's Mocui,
which was given by Your Highness.
I'm just teasing you
and joking around.
Of course I know your name is Mocui.
I realize I've been like this
since I was little.
I'm also aware that I'm Princess Ning'an.
All those questions were only a test.
Mocui,
do you know
where demons reside now?
No, I don't.
Your Highness,
please do not speak of demons again,
or His Majesty will impose
more punishment.
"More"?
Previously,
Your Highness spoke for demons.
His Majesty learned about it,
went absolutely livid,
and ordered to confine Your Highness
to your bedchamber.
Got it.
Your Highness, you cannot go out.
There will be more punishment
if His Majesty finds out,
Your Highness!
Step aside.
We're guarding Yong'an Palace
by imperial order.
We beg for Your Highness's understanding.
You guys will pay for this.
How come I can't use
spiritual power in this place?
Both of you, hurry up.
There are many other places to clean.
Give it to me.
Sure.
Be careful.
Yes.
Alright.
Come with me to check out other places.
Yes.
Sure.
Watch your step.
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
if you run away,
we lowly servants will lose our heads.
Please forgive us.
I'm only forbidden from leaving
Yong'an Palace,
not the bedchamber!
The princess barely carried any authority.
What are these?
Even the books she read are so boring.
[Drunk and seated alone,
to whom shall I tell my sorrow?]
[The waning autumn moon will not be whole.
Snow lies lonely on frontier mountains.]
Did Ning'an write this?
Drunk and seated alone,
to whom shall I tell my sorrow?
The waning autumn moon will not be whole.
Snow lies lonely on frontier mountains.
Where did the Demon Lord hide
a hundred years before my time?
When will I ever find Hong Ye?
[Yong'an Palace]
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
it's time for dinner.
Your Highness?
Your Highness...
Sit down.
Please spare me, Your Highness.
Just put on my clothes
and sleep here tonight.
I promise to be back before dawn.
But I dare not.
Will you undress yourself
or shall I help you?
I'll do it myself.
I beg you, Your Highness.
Please do return before dawn.
The Demon King is coming!
What? What's going on?
Run!
What's happening?
The Feiyu Guard set a trap
to catch the Demon King,
yet the latter still managed to escape!
Run, or you'll die
when the Demon King gets here!
The Demon King?
Feiyu Guards on a demon hunt!
Those who obstruct us will die!
I have no intention of killing.
All I want is to retrieve
the sacred artifact of us demons.
Since it's not in your place,
I'll go search somewhere else.
You demon!
Demon,
you think you can enter and leave
the imperial palace
just as you please?
Then let's see
if you're able to stop me.
[Yong'an Palace]
Hong Ye was formidable.
How did Princess Ning'an
manage to wound him?
Hong Ye didn't recognize me just now.
That means he hadn't known Ning'an
by this moment a hundred years ago.
He could've just fled.
Why did he turn back?
Was it to save me?
But why would he save me?
Does he know who I am or not?
What are you looking at?
You're that maid I just met, right?
Yes, I am.
Well, not exactly.
May I ask if you're here to
deflower a maiden
or to have a clandestine affair?
Aren't you afraid of me?
Why should I be afraid of you?
Don't all you humans
fear being devoured by demons?
How handsome of you.
You don't strike me
as a man-eating monster.
Besides,
if you wanted to eat humans,
you would've done so already,
instead of browsing around over there.
Interesting.
You're still as good-looking as ever.
Who are you really?
I am...
What?
Xiao Yao didn't exist a hundred years ago.
I guess I'll have to acquaint with him
using the identity of Ning'an.
I am Ning'an.
May I have your name?
Has my message been passed along?
[Wang Hong]
Rest assured, sir.
He who dares to spill a word
about what just happened
will make an enemy of us Feiyu Guards.
[Yong'an Palace]
Good.
Has the princess's bedchamber
been searched?
Not yet.
Princess Ning'an
is being confined...
for defending demons.
Don't leave!
-Let go.
-You...
No way.
-Let go.
-I won't!
Let go of me!
As my father says,
persistent pursuit wears down
the strongest resistance.
I must hold onto you.
Let go!
No way!
Is this the etiquette
the human emperor taught you?
Yes.
Hong Ye!
How do you know my name?
I...
Tell me.
I dreamed of you.
A man who looked exactly like you
in my dream told me he was named Hong Ye.
I don't know how that happened.
Even as a royal princess,
I'm nothing
but a poor girl despised by her father
and regarded as a jinx by all
in the imperial palace.
Everyone avoids me.
But finally, you showed up.
Could you please...
stay and talk with me?
I'm confined in my bedchamber all day long
with no one to talk to.
I'm all by myself,
helpless and forlorn.
Just stay and talk with me,
will you?
You're being confined?
This pity play still works on him
as expected.
Yes.
What does it have to do with me?
Your Highness,
have you gone to bed?
Her Highness is sound asleep.
Why not come back in the morning, sir?
You know the consequences
of keeping Feiyu Guards
from carrying out duties.
It's inappropriate to search
Her Highness's bedchamber,
since she's a lady after all.
On top of that,
there's no way Her Highness
would pilfer palace artifacts.
We heard Her Highness
made several failed attempts
to leave the palace today.
Given our duty to safeguard the palace,
we must ensure Her Highness's safety.
Halt.
Her Highness is asleep.
You must not enter.
This is a matter of duty.
Sorry for intruding,
Your Highness.
Out of the way!
Your Highness!
An incident occurred
in the palace tonight.
Was Your Highness disturbed?
Fancy finding Your Highness
in the mood to play the zither
in the middle of the night.
Why haven't you knelt in my presence?
How bold of you!
You...
Y-You...
A-Are you...
the maid I saw earlier?
"Maid"?
Are you suggesting
you saw me earlier?
When?
Where?
I was mistaken.
Your Highness has spent
the entire day in the bedchamber
playing the zither
for stress relief.
We humble servants
are just looking for
missing palace artifacts.
Hope Your Highness
can show some understanding.
By breaking into my bedchamber,
you've completed your task, right?
How dare you!
Your Highness,
you're compassionate about demons.
Why not be compassionate about us too?
We're only carrying out our duties.
Get out!
Get out now!
This is outrageous.
Scram.
I...
mean no offense.
-Please...
-Scram!
They really drove me up the wall.
Mocui.
Yes.
Leave the room as well.
Nobody is allowed in
unless I order otherwise.
Yes.
Hong Ye!
Where are you hiding?
Hong Ye?
I'm here.
Don't break the zither.
Lift your foot.
The other one.
Why are you so interested in this zither?
[Yong'an Palace]
She's so keen on playing the zither.
Princess Ning'an
is not submissive at all,
as opposed to what people say.
She's quite something.
The princess still behaves
with such forbearance
despite years of His Majesty's neglect.
She's certainly no ordinary girl.
From now on,
keep close watch on Yong'an Palace.
[Yong'an Palace]
Yes.
You actually play the zither so well.
Why didn't you tell me before?
"Before"?
Oh, right.
We weren't exactly close before.
This zither
is what demons hold sacred,
named Fuxi.
I came to the imperial palace
specifically for this zither.
I didn't expect it to be in your chambers.
To restore Hong Ye's spiritual power,
you need only collect a single drop
of his tear-essence.
I'll give you the zither,
provided that you do me a favor.
What is it?
Alright.
Let's begin.
Don't blink.
Wave your hand
to send air to your eyes.
Close your eyes.
Try hard.
Harder.
Alright. Try again.
One, two, three.
Cry!
As I already told you,
demons don't easily cry.
I didn't cry
even in the face of catastrophes.
I've never seen my own tears myself.
How ridiculous.
This folly is a waste of time.
Let go.
You're basically robbing me.
This is a sacred artifact of demons.
You humans just seized it from us.
It is now simply being returned
to its rightful owner.
I said let go.
No way.
T-T-This zither is the only gift
that my father has ever given me.
Now you're taking it with a mere claim
that it belongs to demons.
You've even tried to intimidate me,
yelled at me, and bullied me.
I was left alone and miserable as a child.
My mother passed away early.
My father doesn't care about me.
Nobody in all the imperial palace
likes me.
When you appeared,
I thought we could be friends.
But as it turns out,
you only care for my zither.
"Friends"?
After knowing each other
for just a few hours,
do we count as friends already?
I've lived for thousands of years,
yet I've never had a friend.
Perfect.
Then I'll be your friend from now on.
Apart from my tears,
what else do you want?
As long as I can have the zither back,
I'll try my best to meet your needs.
A soft heart lies beneath
Hong Ye's tough exterior.
I'll have to soothe his nerves
while seeking another chance.
Great.
Then would you keep me company
and talk with me?
Tell me
what it's like
outside the imperial palace.
In terms of natural scenery,
Mount Qingyuan alone comprises
countless ridges stretching far away.
Mountains aside,
there are two major seas:
the West Sea and the East Sea.
They're vast and magnificent,
dotted with numerous islands.
Beyond those,
there are many mysterious places
that neither of our races have explored.
This boundless world
is endowed with abundant resources.
Nature gives life
to all sorts of creatures,
which all share in the radiant grace
of the sun and moon.
Not just mountains, rivers,
lakes, and seas,
but every living being
can draw energy from heaven and earth.
Are there pig demons
in the Demons' Valley?
And peony flowers that have just
taken human form?
You said you've never left
the imperial palace.
How do you know so much
about the demon realm?
Do those who have ventured
outside the palace
necessarily have knowledge
of the demon realm?
No.
So, it takes one's heart
rather than one's eyes
to actually learn about something.
For me, understanding is gained
by seeing things
from another's perspective.
All humans want to kill demons,
but you're quite an exception.
That's because I'm no ordinary human.
Oh no.
The look in his eyes...
He's now taking me as Princess Ning'an,
not Xiao Yao.
Don't you dare fall in love with me!
Nonsense!
I met you just a moment ago.
How can I possibly...
This is absolutely absurd.
Who knows what the future holds?
I am a human after all.
I'm just worried
that you might hate me for what I am.
In fact, since humans and demons
are both creatures of this world.
we shouldn't be hostile to each other.
Besides,
you've never stepped outside
the palace gates
or harmed the demon realm.
I won't hate you.
But if you dare offend me again...
I won't.
So we're friends now?
I suppose so.
Do you know how to make noodles?
I feed on the spiritual energy
of heaven and earth.
How would I know how to make noodles?
Then you're in for a treat.
Wait here for me.
Don't go anywhere.
Zhang.
How are the steamed buns coming along?
Almost ready.
I heard you were promoted
to the Imperial Kitchen.
A real blessing, wasn't it?
Yes, sure.
This transfer...
Your Highness!
Please forgive me!
I didn't know Your Highness's presence.
I crave Your Highness's pardon!
You may rise.
I'd like to do some cooking myself.
Have I somehow
failed to please Your Highness
with my cooking?
I beg Your Highness to give me
a second chance.
You've done nothing wrong.
I just feel like
cooking something on my own.
All of you may leave now.
Please spare us, Your Highness!
Once we step out of this room,
we and our families
will all lose our lives.
Fine then.
You can stay and help.
Thank Your Highness.
-Thank Your Highness.
-Get up now.
Is there eel?
Yes.
Any shrimps?
Ginger and scallions?
Yes.
Soy sauce?
Yes, everything Your Highness needs!
Let's get started!
Debone the eel.
Cut it into chunks about 3 fingers wide.
Peel, devein, and butterfly
the shrimps, leaving the tails on.
The dough has to be moderately firm.
Got it.
Your Highness,
the wok is cleaned.
The Imperial Kitchen staff
are really good.
Look how spotlessly clean this wok is.
Bring the ingredients over.
Right away!
Terrific.
Wonderful.
Thanks to Your Highness's instructions,
I'm sure these noodles
will be a heavenly delight.
What a fantastic recipe
of Your Highness's!
Careful, Your Highness.
This chilli powder is rather spicy.
To what extent?
To an extreme extent.
Where tears will well up?
Yes, I guess.
You humans really know how to enjoy life.
Have some more.
Why stare at me?
You look great when you eat.
Is the salt level alright?
Yes.
Don't you find it spicy?
Is it spicy?
Then it must be perfectly seasoned.
What are these for?
Could you peel the onions for me?
I don't know how.
You like eating this?
Yes.
Fine.
Onions are difficult to peel.
I'm just peeling an onion for you.
What's so moving about it?
This snuff powder is a tribute
from foreign states.
A sniff of it is enough
to have one's eyes watering
and nose running.
Hold still.
Yes.
I'll present you something fun.
What on earth are you doing?
Men rarely cry, but they do
when they're struck by true sorrow.
I don't believe
you have no sad story at all.
My father says
making friends
is the greatest joy in life
and worth being celebrated
with many drinks.
Your account of the human emperor
makes him sound less abominable now.
Here you are.
Where's yours?
Right here.
Well...
As a lady within palace walls,
I can't hold my liquor.
Little wine though it is,
it symbolizes heartfelt friendship.
Drink up!
You drank it up?
Didn't you say, "Drink up"?
You really can hold your liquor.
One more jug.
Tell me how many years you've lived.
Several thouand.
I can't recall the exact number.
You must've been through many hardships
during these thousands of years, right?
I can't recall any either.
Cheers.
Have you ever loved a person?
Or a demon?
I'm the Demon King.
I've devoted all my heart to demons.
It has no room for anyone else.
Come on.
Let's have more drinks.
You never get drunk.
Why didn't you tell me that?
So much fine wine of mine has been wasted.
This could have lasted me quite a while.
You're a human princess.
Why stint on a few jugs of wine?
Yeah.
It's not easy to be a princess.
You're quite generous sometimes.
For example, you didn't
hesitate much to return Fuxi Zither to me.
You even asked to make friends with me.
Only with you.
Yeah.
I've never fraternized with another human.
I'd only do that with you.
You don't get it.
You're ignorant of everything.
You don't have spiritual power now.
You might catch a cold for standing
in the wind.
What...
What did you say?
The wind is rising.
It's getting cold.
I'll shield you from the chill.
I'll protect you.
Don't be afraid.
Now you even want to protect me?
Yes.
Why are you treating me this well?
You fool,
I'm trying hard not to do more.
I am...
a demon.
I know.
I know you are a demon—
one who has lived for an age,
and then another, and another.
You've seen humans' deceit
and witnessed your fellow demons
turning against each other.
You don't easily put trust
in humans or demons.
But you still hope to
restore demons' reputation
and clear their name.
You firmly believe
that you must be
responsible for all demons
since you're the Demon King.
That's why
you've been utterly strict with yourself,
why you've cultivated so hard,
and why you've never allowed yourself
to make a mistake.
Right in here,
you've built up
one barrier
after another.
Because you're afraid.
You fear being seen through.
You fear becoming dependent on others.
You fear...
that you'll end up getting disappointed
when you have expectations.
You also fear
that you'll lose something
after attaining it.
That'll only bring you more pain.
So,
each of your barriers in here
has a name.
One is called
"saying what you don't mean."
"never speaking your mind."
Another is called
"too"
"proud"
"to"
"confide."
You've said so much,
as if you know me well.
You old demon,
your words are mean,
but your heart is tender.
You should enjoy
the genuine love of this world.
To laugh
and cry—
that's the way
to complete your demon life!
Are you truly
a human princess?